Guide to the John H. Nixon papers,1952-1995.
Nixon, John H. papers, 1952-1995
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
John H. Nixon papers, 1952-1995.
6336
John H. Nixon
4 cubic ft.
Research Materials, Printed Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reports and studies deriving from Nixon's work as a consulting economist.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Economist.
Ralph M. Parsons, Company, Washington and Los Angeles.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Reports and studies deriving from Nixon's work as a consulting economist with particular reference to the Hong Kong Airport, Cairo water studies, and other projects. Also includes early files on New York State economy and politics, 1950s; "Research Memoranda" from the Committee for Economic Development, Area Development Division by Nixon and others, 1960s; works on real estate indexation, 1990s; and speeches and articles.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Nixon, John H.
Subjects:
Airports.--Design and construction.; Water-supply.; Planning--China--Hong Kong.; Planning--Egypt--Cairo.; Real property.
Places:
New York (State)--Economic policy.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Cairo Papers in Social Science: Living Without Water, 1980 (Box 1)
- Consultants Report to the Director of Civil Aviation - Government of Hong Kong, 1980 (Box 1)
- Hong Kong Air Transport System: Long Term Planning Investigation - System Worth Evaluation, 1973 (Box 1)
- Hong Kong Air Transport System: Long Term Planning Investigation - Air Services Demand Forecast Report, 1973 (Box 1)
- Hong Kong Air Transport System: Long Term Planning Investigation - Night Noise Resurrection Study, 1974 (Box 1)
- Hong Kong Air Transport System: Long Term Planning Investigation - Site Investigation Report, 1974 (Box 1)
- Hong Kong Air Transport System: Long Term Planning Investigation - Working Paper: Initial Site Short Listing, 1973 (Box 1)
- Hong Kong Air Transport System: Long Term Planning Investigation - System Development Plan: Final Report, 1974 (Box 1)
- Hong Kong Air Transport System: Long Term Planning Investigation - Executive Summary, 1975 (Box 1)
- Hong Kong Air Transport System: Long Term Planning Investigation - Alternative Systems Study, 1974 (Box 1)
- Greater Cairo Waterowrks Development Programs: Final Report - Waterworks Master Plan Executive Summary, 1979 (Box 1)
- Greater Cairo Waterworks Development Programs: Rod El Farag Improvement Program, 1978 (Box 2)
- Greater Cairo Waterworks Development Programs: Final Report - Waterworks Master Plan Part I - Immediate Phase, Part II - Staged Development, 1979 (Box 2)
- Greater Cairo Waterworks Development Programs: Final Report - Waterworks Master Plan Appendices, 1979 (Box 2)
- Greater Cairo Waterworks Development Programs: Interim Action Report No. 1 - Metered Water Service for Lower Income Population, 1977 (Box 2)
- Site Selection Survey and Airport Layout Plan for Montgomery County, Maryland, 1969 (Box 2)
- Algerian High Plateaus Industrialization and Transportation Study: Supplement to Vol. I - Industrial Development Program, 1976 (Box 2)
- Greater Cairo Waterworks Development Programs: FY 77 Water System Improvement Projects, 1977 (Box 2)
- Final Report: Djakarta International Airport; Vol. II, Appendix, 1971 (Box 2)
- Algerian High Plateaus Industrialization and Transportation Study: Vol. III - The Algerian Economy in 1990, 1976 (Box 2)
- Metered Water Service Connections Program: Socio-Economic Report on Proposed Service Areas; Appendix D (Box 2)
- Master Plan of the Storm Sewer System for the Eloy Alfaro Parish, Ecuador, 1973 (Box 2)
- Algerian High Plateaus Industrialization and Transportation Study: Vol I. - Industrial Development Program, 1976 (Box 2)
- Djakarta International Airport Study: Vol. I - Study Report, 1971 (Box 2)
- Matered Water Service Connections Program - Socio-Economic Report on Proposed Service Areas (Box 2)
- Final Report - Urban Development, Problems, Issues, and Research Implications, Dec. 15, 1976 (Box 3)
- Committee for Economic Development - Research Memorandum: Financing Urban Transportation, April 5, 1963 (Box 3)
- Committee for Economic Development - Research Memorandum: Key Questions on Urban Transportation, Sept. 10, 1962 (Box 3)
- Committee for Economic Development - Research Memorandum: Fiscal Capacity of State and Local Governments in Relation to Urban Transportation Needs, Sept. 28, 1962 (Box 3)
- Speech - Utica Industrial Management Club; Utica, NY, Jan. 8, 1959 (Box 3)
- Nixon, John H. - Releases, Publicity (Box 3)
- Nixon, John H. (Newspaper Clippings) (Box 3)
- Governor's Conference on Unemployment, May 2, 1958 (Box 3)
- Harriman Economic Statements (Box 3)
- Liberal Party Program (Box 3)
- Davis, Laura (Governor's Office) (Box 3)
- Harriman, Averell, Governor (Box 3)
- Nassau County Planning (Box 3)
- New York State Young Democrats (Box 3)
- Amsterdam, City of (Box 3)
- Annual Messages - Governors Harriman & Rockefeller (Box 3)
- Arden House Conference Reports (Box 3)
- Index of Business Activity (Box 3)
- County Planning (Box 3)
- Long Island Transportation (Box 3)
- Massena Master Plan (Box 3)
- Metropolitan Area Planning (Box 3)
- Metropolitan Area - Regional Planning Conferences (Box 3)
- Metropolitan Problems (Box 3)
- Metropolitan Rail and Transit Problems. (Box 3)
- Metropolitan Regional Council (Box 3)
- Newspaper Clippings - Urban Problems, NY Times (Box 3)
- New York City - Downtown District (Box 3)
- New York Metropolitan Region Study (Box 3)
- NYS Business Climate (O'Brien articles) (Box 3)
- New York State's Economy (Vera Russell) (Box 3)
- New York State Growth (Box 3)
- North Atlantic Ports Rate Equalization Case (Box 3)
- "Positive Approach" Problems (Box 3)
- Price Increases (Box 3)
- Small Business Tax Relief Hearing (Box 3)
- Speech - Hudson-Mohawk Chapter, American Marketing Association, Nov. 17, 1958 (Box 3)
- Speech - NYS Conference of Mayors: Lake Placid, NY, June 3, 1958 (Box 3)
- Speech - Albany Regional Conference of Public Heatlh Workers; Schenectady, NY, April 29, 1958 (Box 3)
- Speech - County Officeres Assocaition; NYS, Syracuse, NY, Feb. 26, 1957 (Box 3)
- Speech - Lions Club; Gloversville, NY, June 19, 1957 (Box 3)
- Speech - Cairo Central School; Cairo, NY, April 11, 1957 (Box 3)
- Speech - League of Women Voters; Clarence, NY, April 2, 1957 (Box 3)
- Speech - Citizens' Action Council of Stamford, Feb. 24, 1965 (Box 4)
- Economic Redevelopment in Five American Communities Columbia Population Seminar, Dec. 9. 1964 (Box 4)
- The State and Economic Development: National Municipal League, Detroit, Nov. 18, 1963 (Box 4)
- Renewing a Community's Economic Base: Commonwealth Conference on Community Development - U. Penn, March 8, 1965 (Box 4)
- Stonier Graduate School of Banking (Rutgers University, NJ) - Notes for Address for Four Years (Box 4)
- Speech - John H. Nixon, U. of Washington, Seattle, April 12, 1962 (Box 4)
- Community Efforts to Rec...Unemployment; RAND Conference on Urban Economics - Santa Monica, CA, Oct. 1964 (Box 4)
- John H. Nixon - Speeches, Addresses, Remarks, Talks, etc. (Box 4)
- Speeches, 1960-65 (Box 4)
- Notes (Box 4)
- Paper - Community Adjustment: The Lessons of Experience (Box 4)
- National Conference on Urban Life - Stimulating Development: Washington D.C., March 30, 1962 (Box 4)
- Saudi Urban Planning Info (Box 4)
- Shapiro Letter, Nov. 30, 1992 (Box 4)
- Public Works Timing (Box 4)
- Wall St. Journal Letter (Box 4)
- John H. Nixon Indexation Letters (Box 4)
- Indexing - AARP (Box 4)
- Indexation - Real Estate, July 1993 (Box 4)
- Tax Fairness Requires Indexing, June 3, 1993 (Box 4)
- Capital Gains Tax Sources (Box 4)
- Indexation Statistics (Box 4)
- Cairo Paper in Social Science - Living Without Water (Box 4)
- Notes on Consideration of Physical Environmental Factors as a Whole in Relation to Health - Sergei N. Grimm (Box 4)
- Prospects for Rehabilitation - Morningside Heights, NYC Housing Study (Box 4)
- Speech - Annual Convention of the Association of Towns (Buffalo, NY): "What can be done to solve interurban and urban problems?", Feb. 13, 1957 (Box 4)
- Nixon / Gerhardt Report: Urban Economic Development (Box 4)
- Egypt Ministry of Planning Report: The Five-Year Plan 1978-1982, Vol. II, Aug. 1977 (Box 4)
- Egypt Ministry of Planning Report: The Five-Year Plan 1978-1982, Vol. II, Aug. 1977 (Box 4)
- Book - Government Control of Lumber Prices in World War II, 1952 (Box 4)
- Book - Government Control of Lumber Prices in World War II, 1952 (Box 4)